Guide to the Seymour Posner Papers WAG.070
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Seymour Posner Papers
1940-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Posner, Seymour
Posner, Ann
WAG.070
5 Linear Feet 5 record cartons and 1 manuscript box.
Seymour Posner (1925-1988) was a pro-labor New York State Assemblyman, who represented the 76th District in the Bronx. He was actively involved with the Workman's Compensation Board, in addition to the Workers Defense League, Inc. Posner was an admitted Socialist who joined the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee during the late 1970s. The papers and photos featured in Posner's collection mostly relate to his service as Assemblyman and his work with the Workman's Compensation Board.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ann Posner, 1989. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1989.002, 1989.007, 1989.010, and 2009.058.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions. It should be noted that Series V, comprising Boxes 5 and 6, is unprocessed but open to researchers.
Historical/Biographical Note
Seymour Posner (1925-1988), New York State assemblyman and labor legislator, was born on May 21, 1925 to Nathan and Fannie Posner. He was raised in the Bronx, New York. In 1942, he enlisted and served in the 3rd Infantry Regiment in France and Germany during World War II, during which he lost hearing in one ear. Upon his return to New York, Posner enrolled at the City University of New York, earning a BS in social science in 1948. He began his active involvement in Democratic politics during this time, as a supporter and officer in the Young Democrats. His involvement with the labor movement also began about this time, as he chaired the organizing committee of Local 371 of the Government and Civic Workers (AFSCME) from 1949 to 1951 and was a member of the New York City Central Labor Council from 1949 to 1954. In 1958 Posner completed the MA program at New York University's School of Public Administration.
Posner became the public relations director for the Urban League of Greater New York in 1958 and served as director of public relations for marches on Washington in 1958 and 1959, and again for the 1963 march led by Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. He also spent several days in a Maryland jail as a Freedom Rider in 1963. Posner served as the community relations director to the Manhattan Borough President for one year (1961-1962) and was Bronx director of the American Jewish Congress (ca. 1962-1964). During this period he worked in public relations and direct-mail marketing of services primarily aimed at the housing market. In 1964 Posner sought and won the 76th A.D. Assembly spot, representing the South Bronx. Despite two consecutive reapportionments of the 76th district in 1965 and 1966, Posner was able to win re-election and became a fixture in the Assembly. He communicated with his constituency via newsletters and flyers. He concentrated on labor-related issues, supporting bills that permitted collective bargaining rights for domestic workers and for workers employed by non-profit, educational and charitable institutions and that guaranteed workman's compensation for farm workers. He sponsored bills on retirement benefits, insurance, and workman's compensation.
In 1972 he began serving on the Assembly Labor Committee, rising to the position of Chairman (1974-1976). He failed in a 1973 bid for the position of Bronx City Councilman at Large, and, in 1978, retired from the Assembly to accept appointment an from Governor Carey to the State Workman's Compensation Board, though his nomination was only narrowly confirmed by the Senate. Posner had some difficulties with two chairmen of the Board, Robert Steingut and Arthur Cooperman, but he did win appointment as the Vice-Chairman of the Board in 1984. Posner took a decidedly pro-union position on the Board and served until June of 1988, when he retired. He acted as the legislative director for the New York City Central Labor Council until his death on November 2, 1988, a span of less than six months.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into three series:
This collection is arranged into five series:
Missing Title
New York State Assembly, 1958-1988
Workman's Compensation Board, 1960-1988
General Files, 1940-1989
Photographs, 1949-1977
Unprocessed Material
Scope and Content Note
The bulk of the collection is comprised of correspondence and clippings, along with photographs, case files, legislative drafts, press releases, flyers, newsletters, lists, transcripts of speeches and reports. The clippings, many of which are from local Bronx newspapers, provide context for legislative material and background on Posner's general activities.
The Seymour Posner Papers primarily document Posner's time as New York State Assemblyman and his involvement with the Workman's Compensation Board. Included in the collection are reminiscences concerning Posner's participation in the Civil Rights Movement and various marches; also featured is limited photographic material on Posner and Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. in Washington, D.C. This collection contains relatively sparse coverage of Posner's activities prior to 1964; additionally, there are not any contemporary documents.
Newsletters.; Fliers (printed matter); Correspondence.; Press releases.; Black-and-white photographs.; Collective bargaining.; Photographs.; Workers' compensation.; Clippings (information artifacts); Labor movement -- United States.; Transcripts.; Lists (document genres); Posner, Ann; Manhattan (New York, N.Y.). Office of the President; Steingut, Robert; Cooperman, Arthur; Urban League of Greater New York; American Jewish Congress
- Series I: New York State Assembly, 1958-1988.
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I: New York State Assembly, 1958-1988 relates to the thirteen years (1965-1978) that Posner served in the New York State Assembly. For most years, there is an inconsistent retention of correspondence. Included are files on legislative issues with which Posner was involved, as well as newsletters sent to constituents, and campaign materials. The Household Worker's Collective Bargaining legislation is particularly well documented.
  - Adelphi Hospital Strike, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adelphi Hospital Strike - Clippings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Albany Medical Center Incident, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Albany Medical Center Incident - Clippings, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Biographical Sketches, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Campaign, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Campaign, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Campaign, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campaign, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Campaign, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Campaign, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campaign (City Council), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Campaign, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campaign, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Campaign, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Campaign, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Civil Service Press Clippings, 1965-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Constituent Correspondence, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Crime, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Department of Labor Application, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Education, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Glue-Sniffing, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Household Workers Articles and Reports, 1974-1983 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining, undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Household Workers Collective Bargaining - Clippings, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Household Workers Minimum Wage, 1965-1971 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Housing, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Housing - Clippings, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Humane Slaughter - Clippings, 1965-1969 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Humane Slaughter, 1958-1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Labor - Clippings, 1965, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Labor, 1966-1976 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Legislative Record, 1958-1975 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Martin Luther King, Jr. Holiday, 1975-1988 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Newsletters, 1965-1978 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - NY State Bird - Bluebird, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Ombudsman Program, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Press Clippings, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Press Clippings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Press Clippings, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Press Clippings, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Press Clippings, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Press Clippings, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Press Clippings, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Press Clippings, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Press Clippings, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Press Clippings, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Press Clippings, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Press Clippings, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Press Clippings, undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Proclamation from City Council, 1988 (Oversize Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Resumes, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Sabbath Observance, 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Speeches, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Tuition Legislation, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - United Bronx Tenants, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Vietnam, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Workman's Compensation Legislation, 1973-1976 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Series II: New York State Workman's Compensation Board, 1960-1988.
  Series II: New York State Workman's Compensation Board, 1960-1988 documents Board procedures, case files and legislation affecting the Board's operation. There is near complete documentation on the Temporary State Commission on Workman's Compensation, a review committee which was formed in 1985 to look into the Board's spending patterns.
  - Cooperman, Arthur, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1984 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Editorials, 1979-1986 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Full Board Reviews, 1968-1981 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Hearing Loss, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Hills v. NYS Police, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Irish Arts Center, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Johnston, Diana, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Labor College, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Labor Theater, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Legislative Resolution from the State of New York, 1988 (Oversize Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Maritime Port Council, 1979-1982 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - NY Committee for Occupational Safety & Health, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - NY Committee for Occupational Safety & Health, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - NY Committee for Occupational Safety & Health - Research, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Omnibus Bill, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Resumes, 1978-1988 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Review Board Procedures, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Sojurner Truth Centennial, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Steingut, Robert, 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Temporary State Commission, 1985-1987 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Temporary State Commission Report, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Temporary State Commission Report, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Temporary State Commission Report, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Temporary State Commission Research Papers, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Turbish v. New York Institute of Technology, 1982-1984 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Workers Defense League, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - WC Bills Pending, 1982-1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - WCB Appointment, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - WCB Articles, 1984-1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - WCB Codes For Officers, 1960-1977 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - WCB Management and Productivity, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - WC Case Opinions, 1978-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - WC Legislation, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Series III: General Files, 1940-1989.
  Series III: General Files, 1940-1989 contains documents which do not fall into the categorizations above; they are mostly mementos and papers from the pre-Assembly years (1940-1964). Posner's work with the Urban League and American Jewish Congress is briefly featured, in addition to post-Workman's Compensation Board materials, including a memorial offered in the New York State Assembly after Posner's death.
  - American Jewish Congress, 1955-1964 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cartoon, 1974 (Oversize Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Factors Affecting NYC Housing Market - thesis, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Housing - Reports, 1958-1958 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - March on Washington, Reminiscences, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Memorabilia, 1940-1949 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Memorabilia, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Memorials, 1988-1989 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Political Activity, 1948-1955 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Proclamation from the State of New York (International Women's Day), 1975 (Oversize Box MSXOS001, Folder 1)
  - Public Relations Material: Housing, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Resumes, 1957-1963 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Urban League of Greater New York, 1957-1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Series IV: Photographs, 1949-1977.
  Series IV: Photographs, 1949-1977 consists of approximately 600 photographs of or with Seymour Posner. It is comprised of portraits, images of Posner speaking or protesting, and group shots of meetings, public events, and demonstrations in which he is included. The majority of the photographs are black and white prints. Very few photographs are dated, but most appear to have been shot between 1968 and 1977.
  - General, 1949, 1966, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - General, circa 1960s, undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - General, circa 1960s, 1975, undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - General, 1973, 1977, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General (I), undated (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - General (II), undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - General (III), undated (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - General (includes photographs of Martin Luther King Jr.), circa 1960s, 1972, undated (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Luncheon, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Negatives, undated (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Series V: Unprocessed Material.
  Series V: Unprocessed Material contains documents on a wide range of subjects.
  - Unprocessed (Box 5)
  - Unprocessed (Box 6)